tickets.com 2001-04-13

# Tickets.com - Privacy Statement

|  |  **ticket·privacy** SM

Tickets.com, Inc., a Delaware corporation with its principal place of business in California (the "Company"), created **ticket·privacy** SM in order to demonstrate the Company's firm commitment to your privacy and privacy-related concerns. The following sets forth the Company's information gathering, use, and dissemination practices. 

It is the Companies policy to allow our customers to control what personal information you provide to us. As a customer of the Company you:

  1. Control what personally identifiable information is collected
  2. Control what the Company can do with the information
  3. Have our commitment to your right of privacy

Privacy Oversight Statement

As a company, Tickets.com believes so strongly in protecting consumer privacy that we are a member of the BBB Online Privacy program. BBBOnline is a wholly owned subsidiary of the Council of Better Business Bureaus. BBBOnLine's mission is to promote trust and confidence on the Internet through, the BBBOnLine Reliability and the BBBOnLine Privacy programs.

The BBBOnLine privacy program features verification, monitoring and review, consumer dispute resolution, a compliance seal, enforcement mechanisms and an educational component. 

The BBBOnLine privacy program: 

  * Awards a "seal" to businesses that post online privacy policies that meet the required "core" principles, such as disclosure, choice, and security.
  * Provides consumer-friendly dispute settlement
  * Monitors compliance through rigorous requirements for participating companies to undertake, at least annually, an assessment of their online privacy practices, and,
  * Offers specific consequences for non-compliance, such as seal withdrawal, publicity and referral to government enforcement agencies.

Our participation in the Privacy Program means we follow the basic principle of the program, "say what you do, do what you say and have it verified."

Information Collection - Notice and Disclosure Statement

From time to time, Tickets.com may ask customers to provide personal information that will help the Company efficiently perform various transactions. That information may be sought as you:

  1. Register for general information
  2. Register for a free trial or demonstration of certain products and services
  3. Sign up or subscribe to products and services
  4. Participate in a special offer or contest

The Company does not collect personal information -- names, addresses, phone numbers, email addresses or credit card numbers -- about you except when you specifically provide such information on a voluntary basis; like, for instance, when you participate in our auction, purchase travel, sports or entertainment tickets, or make inquiries about ticket or reservation availability.

The Company may utilize your personal information in several discrete ways.

  * If you are purchasing sports or entertainment tickets, the Company utilizes your personal information to communicate with you about your ticket order or ticket inquiry. Also, as is always the case whenever you buy a ticket to a sports or entertainment event, the entertainment organization is entitled to know the name and address of all who purchased a ticket. The Company has no control whatsoever over the entertainment organization's use of that information.
  * If you participate in our ticket auction, your Tickets.com username will be visible to anyone visiting the Company's web site, and your email address will be available to other members of Tickets.com in order to facilitate communication about tickets being bought and sold on the auction. At no time, unless you volunteer the same, will any third party know your actual name or any personal information about you. 
  * If you are purchasing travel tickets, the Company utilizes your personal information to communicate with you about your travel plans, and the Company's in-house travel agency also provides information about you to airlines, rental car companies, hotels, and cruise lines, etc., in order to consummate your travel plans.
  * If you come to our web site from one of our strategic partners or register with us, your personal information provided to us may be shared with our strategic partners and used in accordance with their standard policies.
  * As a valued customer of Tickets.com the Company will occasionally contact you, typically by email (or any other way you prefer) in order to notify you of special ticketing promotions, and up-to-date news, custom-tailored to your personal travel, sports, and entertainment interests. Of course, if you do not wish to receive this personalized information, you can always let us know by e-mailing us at [webfeedback@tickets.com](mailto:webfeedback@tickets.com), and we will happily abide by your wishes.
  * Notwithstanding the foregoing, the Company reserves the right to contact you, utilizing your personal information, to inform you of information that might affect your travel, sports or entertainment experience.

Tickets.com users should be aware that if they voluntarily disclose personal information in the auction, chat areas, on bulletin boards, or in classified areas within the Company's web site, that information might be collected and disseminated by third-parties, and result in, among other things, unsolicited inquiries, messages, and offers from third-parties. This third-party conduct is out of the control of the Company.

The Company uses your Internet Protocol (IP) address to help diagnose problems with our computer server, and to administer our web site. Your IP address is used to help identify you, and to gather broad demographic data. Your IP address contains no personal information about you.

The Company does, however, perform statistical analysis of customer usage in order to measure interest in, and use of, the various parts of the Company's web site, and the Company shares that information with current and prospective advertisers, and other interested third parties. But, this information is aggregated data only (statistics, etc.), and contains no personally identifiable information whatsoever.

Tickets.com users should be aware that non-personal information and data may be automatically collected by virtue of the standard operation of the Company computer servers or through the use of "cookies". Cookies are files a web site can use to recognize repeat users, and allow a web site to track web usage behavior. Cookies take up minimal room on your computer and cannot damage your computer's files. Cookies work by assigning a number to the user that has a specific meaning to the assigning web site. Cookies, by themselves, cannot be used to find out the identity of any user. Unless you choose to provide us with information about you, the Company will never know who you are, even though we assign your computer a cookie. Other companies that place advertising on our site also have the ability to assign a different cookie to you in a process that the Company does not control. But since cookies aren't useable for identifying individuals, these advertisers will never know who you are - and the Company will never tell them! If you do not want information to be collected through the use of cookies, your browser allows you to deny or accept the use of cookies. There may, however, be some features on the Company's web site that require the use of cookies in order to customize the delivery of information to you.

Consent/Choice Statement

The Company does not sell or rent personal information about its customers to any third parties at this time. In the event the Company does engage in such commerce in the future, you will have an opportunity to remove yourself from any such lists prior to your inclusion therein by emailing us at [webfeedback@tickets.com](mailto:webfeedback@tickets.com).

Data Quality and Security Statement

The Company maintains strict data security systems that ensure specific individual information will not be made available to any unauthorized person. We use a multi-level security system to control access to information stored for our customers. This is complemented with physical security of our facilities and limited access to certain critical areas.

The Company is committed to educate our employees about the issues and laws surrounding individual rights to privacy. We provide information to all employees on the importance of consumer privacy. We provide ongoing education to our employees on the laws and accepted practices under which the Company operates. All new employees agree, as a condition of employment with us, to safeguard the personal data that is under our control. We ensure that all employees understand the provisions of our Privacy Policy.

The Company is committed to work with recognized trade associations and organizations that support consumer privacy. 

In each country where we operate, we actively participate in the Direct Marketing Association's efforts to maintain and develop appropriate industry guidelines that safeguard the individual's right to privacy. We recognize and actively support sectoral codes of practice and relevant legislation which covers other industry-specific guidelines on privacy such as the European Union Data Protection Act, the recommendations of the Office of Telecommunications in the UK, and the National Health and Medical Research guidelines in Australia. 

Data Protection and Privacy legislation was originally developed in Europe and now exists in many countries worldwide. Wherever the Company operates, we are committed to adhering to the relevant data protection legislation and/or industry codes of practices. 

Privacy Principles for Non USA Based Business

Privacy in the United Kingdom 

Back to [United Kingdom's homepage](http://www.uk.tickets.com/)

By submitting your information, you agree to the following: Tickets.com is a US company (Tickets.com) which sells tickets for venues across the world. In the UK our company is Dataculture Ltd - a Tickets.com company (address: Dataculture, 405 Midsummer Boulevard, Milton Keynes MK9 3BN). Your data will be kept on our database in the US and we will only supply it to a venue from which you choose to purchase tickets. The venue will only share your details with their promoter or visiting company or artist in order for them to contact with you with further information. From time to time we may contact you with details of special offers or other promotions which we think will be of interest to you. 

For more information on our privacy practices or the privacy regulations in your country, you may contact:

or the Data Protection Office at:

Information Line

01625 545 745

e-mail: [mail@dataprotection.gov.uk](mailto:%20mail@dataprotection.gov.uk)

To notify

01625 545 740

e-mail: [mail@notification.demon.co.uk](mailto:%20mail@dataprotection.gov.uk)

Switchboard

01625 545 700

Fax

01625 524 510

DX

20819 Wilmslow

Data Protection in Australia

Back to Australia's home page

The Commonwealth Privacy Act 1998 implements strict privacy protection which Commonwealth and government agencies must observe when collecting, storing, using and disclosing personal information. Other Commonwealth laws contain privacy provisions relating to information about health insurance claims, data matching, information about old criminal convictions and personal information disclosed by telecommunications companies. The Privacy Act applies to the private sector only with respect to tax file numbers and consumer credit information. The Federal Privacy Commissioner has encouraged Australian businesses to develop voluntary industry codes of conduct to meet privacy standards. In February 1998, the Commissioner issued a document entitled "National Principles for the Fair Handling of Personal Information." The National Principles are based on the OECD Guidelines. These Principles address the collection, use, and disclosure of data; data quality and security; openness, access and correction; identifiers, anonymity, trans-border data flows and sensitive information. In December 1998, the Federal Government announced that it intends to enact legislation to strengthen self-regulatory privacy protection in the private sector. They also announced that the legislation that will be introduced would be based on the National Principles. The Company is committed to adherence to industry codes of conduct and/or legislation that will be required to process data in Australia and respects the privacy rights of the citizens of Australia.

For more information on our privacy practices or the privacy regulations in your country, you may contact:

or the Privacy Commissioner's Office at:

Privacy Commissioner's Office

GPO

Box 5218

Sydney, NSW, Australia 1042 

Phone: 1-300 363 992

Fax: 02 9284 9666 

E-mail: [privacy@hreoc.gov.au](mailto:privacy@hreoc.gov.au)

URL: [www.privacy.gov.au](http://www.privacy.gov.au/)

Privacy in the Netherlands

Back to [Netherlands' homepage](http://www.nl.tickets.com/)

The Netherlands enacted the Data Protection Act (DPA or the Act) on July 1, 1989\. The DPA promotes self-regulation, and provides consumers with certain rights, including notice, access to information, disclosure and correction of inaccuracies. It requires those in control of personal data files to take measures to assure only authorized disclosures and ensure informational accuracy. Lastly, the DPA allows consumers to seek and obtain compensation for damages. The Act applies to personal data files relating to living individuals. Collection of data for personal or private use is excluded from its provisions. When certain requirements are met, a corporation may bring an action under the Act's provisions, however, the Act itself does not apply to data concerning corporations. 

The Act creates the Chamber of Registration which is responsible for:

  * monitoring privacy development 
  * advising the cabinet on privacy matters 
  * enforcing the provisions of the Act 

Your Rights as the Consumer

A consumer must be informed of the collection of data within one month in writing. Notice must contain the following:

  * purpose of the file 
  * name and address of file controller 

A consumer must be informed of their right to question the existence, accuracy, and origin of data. 

Information Bureaus 

Information bureaus may gather information that affects the rights of consumer'ss. For example, a credit bureau may gather information relating to a consumer's's creditworthiness. Consent is required for the issuance and dissemination of such information and such consent must be in writing. Data may be issued to a third party if in conjunction with the purpose of the file, on request for research or statistical purposes, or "on the grounds of urgent and important considerations." The Act applies to all civilian collections of personal data, regardless of residency status in the Netherlands. It also applies to foreign files having a Dutch file controller and containing personal data about Netherlands residents. There are certain limited exemptions that may be granted in trans-border data dissemination, however, exemptions are only granted to those countries with adequate data protection laws. The Act limits access to foreign data files dictated by a foreign controller. A total ban on the transfer of data can be issued if it is established that the privacy of an individual in threatened.

For more information on our privacy practices or the privacy regulations in your country, you may contact:

or the Registratiekamer at:

E-mail: [mail@registratiekamer.nl](mailto:mail@registratiekamer.nl)

Registratiekamer 

P.O. Box 93374

PrinsClauslaan 20 

2595 AJ Den Haag 

The Netherlands

Phone: +(31) 70 381 1300 

Fax: +(31) 70 381 1301

Privacy in Canada

Back to Canada's homepage

The Canadian government passed two acts, the Access to Information Act ("AIA") and the Privacy Act on July 1, 1983 to balance the need for data processing with the competing interests of Canadian citizens for protection of their privacy. Although the AIA received more media attention, it is the Privacy Act that guarantees citizens the right to privacy.

The Privacy Act - General Provisions 

The Privacy Act ensures the right of every Canadian citizen and permanent resident: 

  1. to know (with certain exceptions) of the existence of files relating to him or her 
  2. to be able to examine, challenge and correct any information 
  3. to know the purposes of the information collected 
  4. to be consulted as to future use of any information 

Personal information is deemed to include:

  1. race, ethnic origin, religion, age or marital status; 
  2. educational, medical, employment, criminal or bank records;
  3. address, fingerprints, blood type or any identifying number relating to the individual; 
  4. another individual's opinion about the individual; 
  5. the individual's opinions on proposals for a grant; 
  6. correspondence with a government institution; or 
  7. the individual's name, if attached to any personal information. 

For more information on our privacy practices or the privacy regulations in your country, you may contact:

or the Privacy Commissioner of Canada at:

E-mail: [clavoie@fox.nstn.ca](mailto:clavoie@fox.nstn.ca)

URL: [infoweb.magi.com/~privcan](http://infoweb.magi.com/~privcan)

Privacy Commissioner of Canada

112 Kent Street, 3rd Floor 

Ottawa, Ontario K1A 1H3

Phone: 1 800 267 0441 

Fax: 613 947 6850 

TDD 613 992 9190 

Privacy in Hong Kong

Hong Kong enacted the Personal Data (Privacy) Ordinance (Ordinance) which entered into force December 20, 1996. The Privacy Commission Office is an independent statutory body set up to oversee the enforcement of the Ordinance. The Ordinance has as its core purpose the protection of privacy interests of living, identifiable individuals in relation to personal data. It also contributes to Hong Kong's continued economic well being by safeguarding the free flow of personal data to Hong Kong from restrictions by countries that already have data protection laws. The Ordinance binds the government to ensure the protection of privacy rights of its citizens. Where there is a conflict between the Ordinance and any other legislative action or ordinance, the Privacy Ordinance takes precedence. The Ordinance states its mission as: "A data user shall not do an act, or engage in a practice, that contravenes data protection principle unless the act or practice, as the case may be, is required or permitted under this Ordinance."

The Ordinance provides certain rights to consumers including:

  * access 
  * correction or erasure 
  * copies of information held 
  * complaint procedures for denial of access and 
  * compensation for damages suffered as a result of unauthorized disclosure or misuse. 

Consumers must be informed of: the rights and obligations of compliance; penalties or consequences for failure to do so; purpose of the data collection; any anticipated third party disclosure; and rights of access and correction. Personal data should not be kept longer than necessary to the fulfillment of the purpose for which they are collected 

Data transferred to Hong Kong from other jurisdictions will generally become subject to the requirements of the Ordinance. Section 33 of the Ordinance regulates the transfer of data out of Hong Kong. This section provides for an equivalence test of protection, rather than the adequacy test of the EU Directive. It permits transfers to jurisdictions lacking a data privacy regime where the interests of the consumer are otherwise adequately protected. Examples are where consent has been obtained or there are contractual assurances in place that the data protection principles will be respected. 

For more information on our privacy practices or the privacy regulations in your country, you may contact:

or the Privacy Commissioner for Personal Data at:

E-mail: [pco@pco.org.hk](mailto:%20pco@pco.org.hk)

URL: [www.pco.org.hk](http://www.pco.org.hk/)

Privacy Commissioner for Personal Data 

Privacy Commission Office 

Unit 2001 

20/F 

Office Tower

Convention Plaza

1 Harbour Road 

Wanchai, Hong Kong

Phone: 852 2827 2827 

Fax: 852 2877 7026 

Privacy in Germany

Back to [Germany's homepage](http://www.de.tickets.com/)

Data protection in Germany has come in two phases. The Federal Data Protection Act (BDSG) was adopted January 27, 1977. The major provisions came into force January 1, 1978 and the technical and organizational measures became effective on January 1, 1979. The BDSG was then replaced in 1991 by a new data protection act which took advantage of the experiences and technical improvements of the previous years as well as judicial opinions of the Federal Constitutional court.. Data protection in Germany centers around important concepts of general privacy, human rights and the balance between access to information and privacy concerns. Basically, the German data protection law embodies "informationelles Selbstbestimmungsrecht" -- the basic right of the individual to decide on the use and communication of his or her personal data. This tenet is paramount, with the caveat of overriding social or public concerns. The main purpose of the Act is to "protect the individual against his right to privacy being impaired through the handling of his personal data." The Act states that the "processing and use of personal data shall be admissible only if this Act or any other legal provision permits or prescribes them or the consumer's has consented." But the Act may be superseded by the interests of the state. The Act states that insofar as "other legal provisions of the Federation are applicable to personal data, including their publication, such provisions shall take precedence over the provisions of this Act." 

Personal data is defined as "any information concerning the personal or material circumstances of an identified or identifiable individual." Dissemination of personal data to third persons is limited but permissible, as long as there is no threat of harm to the consumer's or his interests.

A consumer has the right of notification of collection of data, notification of content, purpose and identity of recipients and the rights of correction, erasure or blocking. Blocking is defined as the labeling of stored personal data so as to restrict further processing or use. This information must be transmitted to the consumer in writing and free of charge. If a file controller refuses access, a consumer's has the right to appeal to the Federal Commissioner for Data Protection. In general, communication and storage of data is permissible if the business has identifiable and justifiable interests. There are no restrictions, for instance, on information regarding membership in a group, occupation, birth year, name, title, academic degree or address. These categories are not sensitive by their nature and may be of legitimate interest or use of a file controller. Restrictions do apply to sensitive data relating to health, criminal offenses, administrative offenses, or religious or political convictions.

For more information on our privacy practices or the privacy regulations in your country, you may contact:

or the Der Bundesbeauftragte für den Datenschutz at:

E-mail: [de.bund400@bfd.posteingang](mailto:de.bund400@bfd.posteingang)

Der Bundesbeauftragte für den Datenschutz

Postfach 200112

53131 Bonn

Germany

Phone: +(49) 228 819 95 10

Fax: +(49) 228 819 95 50

Privacy in Belgium

Back to [Belgium's homepage](http://www.be.tickets.com/)

Belgium enacted the Belgium Data Protection Act (BDPA) on December 8, 1992, to ensure that personal data may only be processed for clearly described and justified purposes and may not be used in a manner incompatible with these purposes. 

With regard to sensitive personal data, there are more specific, more stringent rules that must be observed by the file controller. These rules apply to three categories of personal data: highly sensitive, medical and judicial data. Highly sensitive data refers to information on the subject's race, ethnicity, sexual orientation or behavior, political activity or opinion, religious and philosophical beliefs and membership in labor unions. Appropriate groups may, of course, keep membership lists.

The consumer's has the right to information, access, correction or deletion of inaccurate or illegally stored data, appeal and information about these rights. The BDPA refers to information collected both directly from and indirectly about the consumer's. This applies to all consumers in Belgium, including foreign consumers, even when further processing occurs outside of Belgium.

The consumer's has the right to access information directly or through the Privacy Commission. For direct access, the consumer's must submit a written request to the company and can be charged a fee. The company must respond within 45 days with the information. A consumer has a right to correct any misinformation collected free of charge. They must submit a request to the company who must respond within one month and inform any consumer of the correction or deletion. The company must keep the identity of any third consumer for at least one year. A consumer's has the right to appeal any adverse decision through a complaint to the Privacy Commission or before the Chairman of the Court of First Instance. A consumer has the right to be informed of these rights and their methods of exercise. The BDPA doesn't explicitly prohibit or restrict the merging of personal data from different

For more information on our privacy practices or the privacy regulations in your country, you may contact:

or the Commission de la Protection de la Vie Privée at:

E-mail address: [privacy@infoboard.be](mailto:privacy@infoboard.be)

Commission de la Protection de la Vie Privée

Boulevard de Waterloo 115

Rue de la Regence 61

B - 1000 Brussels 

Belgium 

Phone: (32) 2 542 7200

Fax: (32) 2 542 7212 

Privacy in Italy

Italy enacted the Processing of Personal Data Act (the Act) in September, 1993\. The Act is designed to "ensure that the processing of personal data is carried out by respecting the rights, fundamental freedoms and dignity of natural persons, especially as related to privacy and personal identity..." Personal data is defined under the Act as "any information relating to natural or legal persons, bodies or associations that are or can be identified, even indirectly, by reference to any other information including by a personal identification number..." The law applies to the processing of personal data carried out by any person on Italian soil. It does not apply to data collected for purely personal use, provided that the data are not intended for systematic communication or dissemination. The Act applies to the processing, "on the State's territory, of personal data kept in a foreign country."

All data collected must be:

  * Processed lawfully and fairly 
  * Collected and recorded for specific purposes 
  * Accurate and, when necessary, kept up to date 
  * Adequate, relevant and not excessive to the stated purpose of collection 
  * Kept in a form that permits identification of the consumer for no longer than is necessary for the purpose of collection. 

A consumer has certain rights in regard to the collection of data including: 

  * The purpose of collection 
  * An opt in for data collection 
  * The consequences for failure to provide data 
  * Any third party transmission anticipated 
  * The name, denomination or trade name, domicile, residence or registered office of the company processing and/or storing the data 

For more information on our privacy practices or the privacy regulations in your country, you may contact:

or the Data Protection Authority at:

E-mail: [mc7796@mclink.it](mailto:)

URL: [www.privacy.it](http://www.privacy.it/)

Data Protection Authority 

Via Della Chiesa Nuova, 8

00186 Rome 

Italy

Telephone: + (39) 6 6889 2135

Fax: + (39) 6 6889 2140

Privacy in Denmark

Unlike the other Scandinavian countries, Denmark has passed two acts relative to the protection of privacy and access to information: the Private Registers Act and the Public Registers Act. These acts were adopted by the Danish Folkerting (Parliament) in 1978 and became law January 1, 1979. Amendments were made in 1987. The acts affect "personal data" defined as "data that are referable to identifiable individuals even if such referral presupposes knowledge of the personal registration number or any particular means of identification of such individual." Personal data is data that permit, in any form, directly or indirectly, the identification of the natural persons to which they relate, irrespective of whether the processing is done by a natural or legal person. 

A consumer now has the right to know what is registered about him and may submit a request of access once every 12 months. Response must be within four weeks and complaints regarding denial or delay are made to the DSA. 

Tickets.com will ensure that: 

  * The purposes of data collection and processing are being clearly specified
  * Only information that is relevant and necessary for the original purpose is being processed 
  * Our customers will be able to contact us to obtain what information we are storing to determine that the information is up to date and accurate 
  * Personal information is not kept any longer than required 

Personal information will only be processed with the your consent. You are entitled to withdraw consent at any time. 

Personal information may be transferred to other countries. The Company will obtain approval from the DSA prior to any transfer so that the DSA can determine if that country can secure adequate data protection. Adequate protection will be decided based on the type of data to be transferred, the purpose of the transfer, the country of (the data's) origin, the country of (the data's) destination, as well as data protection rules and guidelines in place in the receiving country. Data may be transferred with the your consent if the transfer is considered necessary for the completion of a purchase on our site.

In addition, Danish regulatory authorities may permit the transfer of personal data to countries lacking adequate protection, if the data controller can provide satisfactory guarantees for the protection of the data subject. The regulatory authorities will notify the European Commission and the EU member states about any data transfers under the latter rule. 

Our Obligations to You and Your Rights 

We are committed to protecting your right to privacy. We have demonstrated this commitment by agreeing to the following:

  * We will always inform you is collecting and processing the data you provide
  * We will always inform you about the purpose for which the data is being processed 
  * We will try to provide additional information that the Company determines necessary to protect your rights 
  * Upon request from you we will inform you about what kind of information is being processed, for what purpose, and who has access to the data
  * You may, for valid reasons, object to the processing of specific data and request the correction or deletion of erroneous information
  * You may, for any reason, object to the processing of data for marketing purposes

For more information on our privacy practices or the privacy regulations in your country, you may contact:

or the Registertilsynet at: 

E-mail address: [sekretariat@registertilsynet.dk](mailto:sekretariat@registertilsynet.dk)

URL: [www.registertilsynet.dk](http://www.registertilsynet.dk/)

Registertilsynet

Christians Brygge 28 4 sal

1559 Copenhagen V

Denmark

Phone: (45) 33 14 38 44 

Fax: (45) 33 13 38 43 

Privacy in Brazil

There are no existing privacy laws in Brazil. The Senate is considering a bill entitled SENATE BILL No. 61 which would place some limits on the collection and use of personal data.

The Company takes your privacy concerns very seriously. If you still have concerns about privacy issues after reading ticket·privacysm, please contact us at [webfeedback@tickets.com](mailto:%20webfeedback@tickets.com).

**ticket·privacy** SM is effective as of November, 1999, and as amended from time-to-time. **ticket·privacy** SM is a statement of our current policy and is not intended to and does not create any contractual or other legal rights in or on behalf of any party.
